And the answer is no, there is no solution that the agent could come up
答案是不可以 agent 找不到任何解决方案
with, because Bucharest doesn't appear on the map.
因为 Bucharest 并没有显示在地图上
And so the agent doesn't know any actions that can arrive there.
因此 agent 也找不到任何到达那里的方法
So let's give the agent a better chance.
所以 让我们给 agent 一个更好的机会
Now we've given the agent the full map of Romania.
现在 我们向 agent 给出了 Romania 的完整地图
The start is in Arad.
起点在 Arad
And the destination or goal is in Bucharest.
终点在 Bucharest
And the agent is given the problem of coming up with a sequence of actions
agent 需要给出一系列行为
that will arrive at the destination.
根据这些行为 最终到达目的地 解决问题
Now is it possible for the agent to solve this problem?
现在 agent 有可能解决这个问题吗
And the answer is yes.
答案是可以
There are many routes or steps or
这里有很多种行动的路线、 步骤或序列
sequences of actions that will arrive at the destination.
能到达目的地
Here's one of them,
这是其中一个
Starting out at Arad, taking this step first, then this one,
从 Arad 开始 先走这步 再走这步
then this one, then this one and then this one to arrive at the destination.
接下来走这步 再走这步 然后走这步就可以到达目的地了
So that would count as a solution to the problem.
这也算是这个问题的一个解决方案
It's a sequence of actions chained together that are guaranteed to get us
这些连在一起的行为序列能确保我们达成目标
Now let's formally define what a problem looks like.
现在 让我们来正式的定义这个问题
A problem can be broken down into a number of components.
该问题可以分解分成若干个部分
First, the initial state that the agent starts out with.
首先是 agent 的起始状态
In our route finding problem,
在我们的路线查询问题中
the initial state was the agent being in a city of Arad.
起始状态为 agent 在 Arad 这个城市里
Next, a function, actions that takes a state as input and returns a set of
接下来 是一个函数 函数名为 Actions 该函数以一个状态作为输入
possible actions that the agent can execute when the agent is in this state.
并且返回可能的行为的集合 这些行为是 agent 在当前状态下所能执行的
In some problems,
在一些问题中
the agent will have the same actions available in all states.
agent 在所有状态下都拥有相同的行为
And in other problems,
在另一些问题中
they'll have different actions dependent on the state.
它们当前的行为取决于当前的状态
In the route finding problem, the actions are dependent on the state.
在路线寻找问题中 行为取决于当前状态
When we're in one city, we can take the routes to the neighboring cities but
当我们在一个城市的时候 我们仅可以选择到邻近城市的路线
we can't go to any other cities.
而不能到除此之外的其它城市
Next we have a function called result which takes as input a state and
接下来 我们有一个叫 result 的函数 该函数的输入为一个状态和一个行为
an action and delivers as its output a new state.
然后输出一个新的状态
So, for example, if the agent is in the city of Arad and
比如说 agent 在 Arad 这个城市
takes, that would be the state.
这是当前状态
And takes the action of driving along route E671
并且 采取了沿着 E671 路线到 Timisora 的行为
towards Timisora, then the result of applying that action in that state
采取这个行为的结果是
would be the new state where the agent is in the city of Timisoara.
达到了一个 agent 在 Timisora 这个城市的新状态
Next, we need a function called GoalTest,
接下来 我们需要一个称之为 GoalTest 的函数
which takes a state and returns a Boolean value, true or
输入为状态 输出为一个 Boolean 类型的值 true 或 false
false, telling us if this state is a goal or not.
这会告诉我们当前状态是否是目标状态
In the route finding problem,
在路线查找问题中
the only goal would being in the destination city, the city of Bucharest,
唯一的目标是到达目标城市 Bucharest
and all the other states would return false for the GoalTest.
除此之外的所有其它状态在 GoalTest 函数中都会返回 false
And finally, you need one more thing, which is a Path Cost function,
最后 你还需要一个东西 就是路线开销函数 Path Cost
which takes a path, a sequence of state,
输入为一条路径 就是一系列状态、行为、转换
action, transitions, and returns a number, which is the cost of that path.
并且 这会返回一个数字 这就是这条路径的开销
Now, for most of the problems we'll deal with,
现在 对于我们将会处理的大部分问题
we'll make the Path Cost function be additive so
我们都会附加 Path Cost 函数
that the cost of a path is just the sum of the cost of the individual steps.
这个问题中 一条路径的总开销就是每一步开销的和
And so
因此
we'll implement this Path Cost function in terms of a Step Cost function.
我们将会以 Step Cost 函数来实现 Path Cost 函数
The Step Cost function takes a state,
Step Cost 函数的输入为一个状态
an action, and the resulting state from that action and
一个行为和该行为的输出状态
returns a number n which is the cost of that action.
返回数字 n 表示了该行为的开销
In the route finding example, the cost might be the number of miles
在路线查找问题中 开销可能是行驶的路程长度
traveled or maybe the number of minutes it takes to get to that destination.
或者 也可能是到达目的地所要花费的时间